Guide to the Ron Meisel Photographs of Coney Island 2005-2008 PR 377
New-York Historical Society
Ron Meisel photographs of Coney Island
2005-2008
New-York Historical Society
Meisel, Ron, 1952-
PR 377
3.5 Linear feet in 1 oversize flat folder
This collection consists of 10 color photographs of Coney Island, taken by photographer Ron Meisel (1952-) between 2005 and 2007. Images include amusement park attractions and participants in the annual Mermaid Parade. Also included is a small exhibition catalog, "Greetings from Coney Island" from a 2008 exhibition of Meisel's photographs at the Brooklyn Public Library.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 10 color photographs of Coney Island, taken by photographer Ron Meisel (1952-) between 2005 and 2007. Images include amusement park attractions and participants in the annual Mermaid Parade on the boardwalk. Also included is a small exhibition catalog, "Greetings from Coney Island" from a 2008 exhibition of Meisel's work at the Brooklyn Public Library.
Eight of the photographs are panoramic photos taken on color negative film and scanned on an Epson scanner. All of the photos were printed on archival paper using an Epson 4800 printer with Epson Ultrachrome K3 inks. The 8 panoramic photos measure 17"x42" and the remaining 2 photos measure 17"x22".
Biographical / Historical
Photographer Ron Meisel was born in New York City in 1952. He worked as a computer programmer and consultant form 1972-2001. Meisel joined the Soho Photo Gallery, a cooperative photography gallery, in 2003, and began photographing Coney Island in 2004.
Arrangement
The photographs are arranged chronologically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift/Purchase 2007.
Five photographs were purchased and five photographs were the gift of the artist, Ron Meisel.
Coney Island (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; Parades -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.
- Cyclone with Mermaid Parade Balloon, 2005 (Folder OS FF1)
- Vertical Parachute Jump, 2005 (Folder OS FF1)
- Astroland Park with Happyface and bottom half of Wonder Wheel, 2006 (Folder OS FF1)
- Beach Scene, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Cole Bros. Circus Tent, Ticket Window, and Refreshment Trucks, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Cole Bros. Circus Truck and Wonder Wheel, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Mermaid Parade with Pink Umbrella, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Mermaid Parade with Shrimp Hats, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Nathan's Sign with American Flags, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- Wonder Wheel at Night, 2007 (Folder OS FF1)
- "Greetings from Coney Island," exhibition catalog, 2008 (Folder OS FF1)